## Clayton Seitz

### cwseitz@uchicago.edu cwseitz.github.io

#### **OBJECTIVE**

My research focuses on a mathematical description of memory formation and inference in spiking neural networks (SNNs). In general, I am interested in the application of information theory and statistical physics to simultaneously describe dynamical states and information transmission in SNNs. I focus on their storage limits ability to compress incoming signals

### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science, Biophysics

University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, Winter 2021

Thesis: Towards a theory of stable cell assembly formation in excitatory-inhibitory neuronal networks

Bachelor of Science, Physics

Purdue University, Indianapolis, IN, 2019

Minor: Mathematics

Bachelor of Science, Informatics

Luddy School of Informatics, Computing, and Engineering, Indiana University Bloom-

ington, 2019

Concentration: Mathematics

# COMPUTER SKILLS

Languages & Software: Python, Tensorflow, C, Git, LaTeX, Bash

## EXPERIENCE

Research Software Developer

Indiana University, Indianapolis, IN

• Develop an image processing software pipeline for high-throughput quantification of images in fluorescent microscopy

• Utilize high performance computing clusters for image segmentation, single particle tracking, and image registration

### Undergraduate Researcher

2019-2020

2019-2021

- Utilize time-correlated single photon counting (TCSPC) to characterize the sub-Poissonian emission of organic quantum dots dispersed in a thin film of poly-methyl methacrylate (PMMA)
- Design and utilize a 3-color imaging protocol to perform single-molecule imaging of mRNA transcripts in human epithelial kidney and osteosarcoma cells

### Undergraduate Tutor

2018-2019

• Tutored undergraduate students in introductory physics courses covering classical mechanics, classical electromagnetism, circuit analysis, and modern physics

	<ul> <li>Information Security Intern</li> <li>Liberty Mutual Insurance</li> <li>Performed attestation testing on externally facing servers</li> </ul>	2018-2019
AWARDS	PS-ON Annual Investigator Meeting Travel Award Purdue University, Indianapolis, IN	2019
	Hudson and Holland Scholarship for Diversity and Inclusion Indiana University, Bloomington, IN	2013-2017
	Founders Scholar Indiana University, Bloomington, IN	2013-2017
	Cigital Scholarship Indiana University, Bloomington, IN	2016-2017
	Deans List Indiana University, Bloomington, IN	2013-2019

# PUBLICATIONS